Jeff Micklos

http://jeffmicklos.com • jeffmicklos@gmail.com • 619-993-9889

ABSTRACT

Front-end developer who is well versed in the best practices of development, from conception to deployment. Keen eye for grid-based design and pixel perfect placement. A love for writing semantic and standards compliant code, which renders flawlessly across all browsers. Expertise in Javascript, including libraries, such as jQuery, Prototype and Google Closure. Server-side programming skills that are fully realized within a user-centered environment. A serial side-projecter with a huge desire to keep learning.

EXPERIENCE

Everlane – Software Engineer

http://everlane.com - March 2012 - Present

Making a beautiful and intuitive online shopping experience. Moving fast, constantly iterating, testing and optimizing. Javascript, jQuery, Ruby, Heroku, MySQL, Love.

- Built a Javascript framework for UI components
- Responsible for mocking up wireframes and interaction models
- Constantly championing the use of consistent and well-formatted typography

Yelp – Front-End Software Engineer

http://yelp.com - June 2010 - March 2012

Worked on the front lines of local business review site, Yelp.com. Wrote and deployed (via Git) HTML, CSS, Javascript and Python in daily test driven iteration cycles. First engineer to bridge the gap and do design as well.

- Acted as an internal evangelist for more semantic micro-format usage and progressive enhancement by way of HTML5 and CSS3
- Lead front-end engineer on Yelp's daily-deal feature, similar to Groupon
- Lead designer and engineer on Yelp's mobile website

Webtape - Chief Architect

http://onwebtape.com - November 2007 - 2010

The site gives users the ability to upload photos, write blog entries, share Youtube videos and Flickr photos. Facebook integration via the PHP and JS libraries give users the ability to share posts across both sites and allows Facebook users to comment on Webtape posts via open authentication (OAuth). oEmbed integration allows users to share content from basically anywhere on the Internet.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science - Web Design & Interactive Media

Art Institute of California - San Diego - October 2005 - June 2009